翻译：草草  CS漫画家小明  潇湘月影  帆大大  木浅薰
翻译：鱼小姐啦  Reginamoon  校对：潇湘月影  油炸电风扇
时间轴：若林  永远的永远  今   阿丹
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第四季   第十五集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
Previously on Suits
我只是想告诉你
I just wanted to tell you
我很感激你跟他和好了
that I appreciate you patching things up with him.
为我爱的人做什么都愿意
I would do anything for the woman that I love...
他们会尽其所能地找我们麻烦
They are gonna come at us any way they can,
而他们一旦动手
and when they do,
出问题的就不是热感应器
it's not gonna be about heat sensors,
而是你了
it's gonna be about you.
但我知道  那公司里除我之外
I know I'm not the only guy in that company
还有人知道感应器全都坏了
that knows those sensors are faulty.
抱歉  你要什么来着
I'm sorry. What is it you need again?
过去六个月以来的所有维修订单
All the maintenance work orders from the past six months.
没有授权我不能给你
I can't let you have that without authorization.
你听说过国家运输管理局吗
Have you heard of the National Transportation Safety Board?
那是你的秘书非法获取证据
That's your secretary unlawfully gathering evidence,
意味着我们根本不会达成和解
which means there will be no settlement of any kind.
明天  我就把这段视频发给地检
And tomorrow, I'm sending this to the district attorney.
你所说的
Your whole story
关于路易把他名字弄上墙的办法都是瞎扯的
about how Louis got his name on the door is bullshit.
杰夫
Jeff.
结束了  杰西卡
It's over, Jessica.
我们结束了
We're done.
难以置信  你真让他们承认过错了
I can't believe you actually got them to admit what they did.
你最好相信  这是跑不了的
You better believe it, because it's happening,
如果没你帮忙  也不会成功
and it wouldn't be happening without you.
你是说如果不是我贪心
You mean without me being greedy.
乔  我没这个意思
Joe, that's not what I was gonna say.
不不  我知道你不觉得
No, no, no, I know that you don't think
我在乎这些人  但我在乎
I care about these people, but I do.
但我也是个普通工人
But I'm also a working stiff.
我这辈子都在领工资
I go paycheck to paycheck for my whole life,
然后遇上了这种事
and then a thing like this--
可以扭转你的人生
Could turn your whole life around.
你这样的人可能无法理解
Guy like you might not be able to understand that.
我理解
I understand.
这事定了吗
So it's a done deal?
了结还要几天时间
Might take a few days to finalize,
但没错
but yeah.
这事成了
It's happening.
我保证
You have my word.
你不错  罗斯先生
You're all right, Mr. Ross.
哈维  你晚上只来过几次
Harvey, you know the only times you've been here at night
一次是那顿糟糕的晚宴
were the god-awful dinner party--
还有另一次
And the other time.
这次不是那样
Well, this isn't that.
我想知道自由铁路公司
I want to know why Liberty Rail
为什么会有你在他们资料室的录像
has a video of you in their file room.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
我是说我们的铁证
I'm talking the fact that our smoking gun
刚刚作废了
just became inadmissible.
-哈维  -你怎么拿到那些文件的
- Harvey-- - How'd you get those documents?
你是问我是否做了违法的事吗
Are you asking if I did something illegal?
我可没有
Because I didn't.
他们去找地检官了
Well, they went to the D.A.,
也就是说他们认为你做了
which means they think you did,
所以我再问你一遍
so I'm gonna ask you one more time,
你怎么进入他们资料室的
how did you get in their file room?
是他们开门让我进去的
By walking through the door they buzzed open.
他们为什么那么做
And why would they do that?
因为我是我
Because I'm me.
这什么意思
What the hell does that mean?
意思是  我让那个女的以为
It means that I led the woman to believe
我是华盛顿来的官员
that I was an official from Washington.
让那人相信
Led them to believe it,
还是你自己说的
or flat out told them?
因为前者会毁了我们的案子
Because one kills our case
后者会让你陷入大麻烦
and the other puts you in a world of shit.
哈维  我不傻
Harvey, I'm not an idiot,
我不喜欢别人当我傻
and I don't appreciate being treated like one.
我说了  我没违法  我就没违法
I told you I didn't do anything illegal, and I didn't.
不傻
Not an idiot?
那你为什么要去那儿
What the hell were you doing there in the first place?
-哈维  -是迈克的主意  是吗
- Harvey. - It was Mike's idea, wasn't it?
不  他完全不知道
No, he didn't even know about it.
-你去哪  -去见迈克
- Where are you going? - To see Mike.
我说了  他不知道我要那么做
I told you, he didn't even know I was going to do it.
我不管  他之后绝对是知道的
I don't care, because he sure as hell knew after.
走
Let's go.
我真为你骄傲
I am so proud of you.
我以前也做到过
I've done that before.
不是那个啦
I'm not talking about that.
我是说你的案子
I'm talking about your case.
你有信念  你争取
You believed in it, and you fought for it,
我就喜欢你这点
and I-- I love that about you.
我就喜欢你喜欢我这点
And I love that you love that about me.
有人这么夸你
When a person gives you a compliment like that,
你是要夸回去的
you're supposed to give one back.
我夸了啊
But I just did.
我说喜欢你喜欢我这点
I said that you love that I love that about me.
如果我说
And what if I said I love that
我喜欢你喜欢我喜欢你这点呢
you love that I love that about you?
你是什么感觉
How would that make you feel?
感觉好累
So tired.
我们都知道你为什么这么累
Well, we both know why you're so tired.
因为我太厉害了
Yeah, because I'm so good.
你不喜欢我这点吗
Don't you love that about me?
你知道唐娜靠撒谎进入了那家公司
You knew Donna bullshitted her way into that company
还让我们使用那些维修订单
and you let us use those work orders?
你怎么知道的
How did you find out?
那不重要
It doesn't matter how I found out.
回答问题
Answer my question.
对  我知道  这有什么  我们赢了
Yes, I knew, but what difference does it make? We won.
我们没赢
We didn't win,
因为伊凡·施密斯有唐娜在他们办公室的视频
because Evan Smith has video of Donna in their offices.
-什么  -她也知道吗
- What? - She know about this too?
哈维  她只是想逼我们
Harvey, she's just trying to strong-arm us.
你听到了没有啊
Are you listening to me?
他们有对方律师的秘书去
They have the opposing counsel's secretary
他们资料室的证据
poking around in their goddamn file room.
如果我是地检官  我肯定会进行调查
If I were the D.A., I'd sure as hell look into it.
-地检官  -没错  地检
- The D.A.? - Yeah, the D.A.
哈维  他们放她进去的
Harvey, they let her in.
是你的说法  他们会说是诈骗
According to you, but they're gonna claim fraud
或偷窃  或其他什么
or theft or any number of things.
你要怎么办
What are you gonna do?
我要和解放弃案子
I'm making a deal to drop this case,
我要这么办
that's what I'm gonna do,
我一达成协议你就去办文书
and you're gonna file the paperwork as soon as I do.
你要毫不反抗
So you're just gonna let this woman
让这女人勒索你吗
blackmail you without a fight?
没错
You're damn right I am.
哈维  我们还是可以拿下案子并...
Harvey, we can still win this case and clear--
没有案子了
There is no case,
就算有我也不在乎
and I wouldn't give a shit about it if there was.
我在乎唐娜
I care about Donna.
你觉得我不在乎吗
And you think I don't?
你那么在乎她
You care so much for her?
就去起草文件
Then draw up those papers,
因为我要通知伊凡这事结束了
because I'm letting Evan know it's over.
你来做什么
What are you doing here?
我们有麻烦了
We have a situation.
事关律所的命运吗
Is the fate of the firm hanging in the balance?
-不  -那我就不在乎
- No-- - Then I don't give a shit.
你告诉马龙了  是吗
You told Malone, didn't you?
我没来得及
I didn't get a chance to tell him,
他自己先查清楚了
because he had already figured out
我一直在跟他撒谎
that I had been lying to him this whole time.
-我很遗憾  -你遗憾
- I'm sorry. - Oh, you're sorry.
今早我以为我能跟他去度假两周
This morning I thought I was going away with him for two weeks.
现在我都不知道他还会不会再见我
Now I don't know if I'm ever gonna see him again.
他辞职了吗
He quit?
他还没来得及跟我说他的职业计划
He didn't get around to giving me his career plans.
要我去替你跟他谈吗
You want me to talk to him for you?
不  这是我的麻烦
No, this is my mess.
我自己会解决
And I will take care of it myself.
明天再说吧
You can take care of it tomorrow.
现在  我要给你倒杯酒
Right now, I'm making you a drink.
欢乐之歌还是抓蛋狂人
Zipadeedoodah or Grab My Sack?
-什么  -信使服务
- What? - Messenger service.
我们用哪家
Which one do we use?
-我...  -算了
- I-I-- - You know what?
随便用哪家  办妥就行
Use whoever you want. Just take care of it.
路易  你自己不是有秘书吗
Louis, don't you have your own secretary?
诺玛吗  我哪都找不到
Oh, you mean Norma, who I can't find anywhere,
她大概又请假了
who is probably taking the day off again?
去年  她想植树节请假
Last year, she tried to get Arbor Day off,
我叫她去她的树
and I told her to blow a goddamn tree
给我来上班
and get her ass in here.
告诉你  路易
You know what, Louis?
这36年来  诺玛才请了4天假
Norma has taken 4 days off in the last 36 years.
你能不能别对她那么苛刻
Why don't you back the hell off of her.
你这是怎么了
What the hell is the matter with you?
你一般会像个四十年代动作片里的无业游民
You usually jump on the Norma bashing train
跳上那辆猛烈批判诺玛的列车
like a hobo in a 1940s action movie.
-抱歉  我只是  -怎么了
- I'm sorry, I just... - What?
我扯谎混进自由铁路公司
I bullshitted my way into Liberty Rail
拿了些文件
to get some documents.
监控录像拍到了我
They caught me on video,
现在他们威胁要起诉
and now they're threatening to press charges.
你怎么不说话
You're not saying anything.
没事  不要紧
It's nothing. It's fine.
那你为什么一副很担心的样子
Then why did you look so concerned?
我很担心  但是他们威胁要起诉
I was concerned, but they're threatening charges,
意味着他们有所图
which means they want something,
我了解哈维  不论他们想要什么
and I know Harvey, and whatever it is they want,
他都会想办法满足他们的
he'll find a way to give it to him.
好吧
Okay.
谢谢  路易
Thanks, Louis.
我帮你搞定那个
I'll take care of your stuff.
不不  你挺忙的
No, no. You have enough on your mind.
我自己搞定吧
I'll take care of it myself.
斯佩克特先生  别开口
Mr. Specter, don't tell me.
我猜你是来谈保尔森女士的事
You're here to talk about Ms. Paulsen.
我是来告诉你  你的意思我懂了
I'm here to tell you you made your point.
我是什么意思
And what point is that?
如果你放弃起诉唐娜
If you drop any charges against Donna,
我们就撤销对你们的诉讼
we'll drop the lawsuit against you.
这好像不太公平
Well, that's not a very even trade.
我是在你机会  让你的当事人摆脱谋杀罪名
I'm giving your client the chance to get away with murder.
据我所知
Last I checked,
我的当事人可没被起诉谋杀
my client wasn't being charged with murder,
我也不需要你放弃诉讼
and I don't need you to drop your suit,
因为罪名根本不成立
because you have no case.
不成立
No case?
你的当事人放任一辆失灵的火车运行
Your client put a faulty train on those tracks,
死了人  而他们从一开始就知道会发生这种事
people died, and they knew it could happen the whole time.
可你没有证据
And you have no proof.
按我们那儿的规矩
And where I come from,
想让我别再追查  你就得跟我做笔交易
you cut a deal with me to make sure I stop looking.
那我猜我们是从不同地方来的
Then I guess we come from different places,
因为我把录像交给地检
because I didn't give that video to the district attorney
不是为了跟你做交易
to leverage you into a deal.
而是为了彻底击溃你
I did it to blow you out of the water.
这事关一个人的一生
This is a person's life.
也许你派她偷我客户东西之前
Maybe you should have thought of that
就该想到这些
before you sent her to rob my client.
伊凡  我很在意这个女人
Evan, I care about this woman.
听着  我理解
Look, I understand.
她可能已经为你工作了很久
She's probably worked for you for a long time.
也许你们还时不时滚滚床单
Maybe you sleep together once in a while.
但我的工作是尽我所能地
But my job is to defend my client
维护我当事人的利益
to the best of my abilities,
我也正打算这么做
and that's exactly what I'm going to do.
天啊
Holy shit.
你不会已经把支票带来了吧
You can't possiblely have a check already.
我没有支票  乔
I don't have a check, Joe.
我们不得不撤销指控
We have to drop the case.
你说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
我们昨晚还一起喝了酒
We had drinks last night.
是的  昨晚我们手上还有
Yeah, we also had proof last night,
而现在  没有了
and now we don't.
-为什么  -事情很复杂
- Why not? - It's complicated.
你知道  很多繁琐的法律程序
You know, it's a lot of legal rigmarole...
少用高人一等的口气跟我说话
Hey, don't talk down to me.
我没有用高人一等的口气跟你说话
I'm not talking down to you.
但我也没法站在这
But I'm also not gonna stand here
跟你解释民事诉讼程序
and explain civil procedure.
也许我是不懂民事诉讼程序
Maybe I don't understand civil procedure,
但如果事有蹊跷
but I know enough to understand
我还是能看出来的
when something doesn't add up.
我们拿到证据的方式不正当
We got the evidence the wrong way.
那就用正当的方式啊
Well, get it the right way.
传唤之类的
Subpoena it or something.
我不能
I can't.
你说不能是什么意思
What do you mean, you can't?
那笔钱可以改变我的人生
That money was gonna change my life.
如果你想找其他律所
And if you want to go to a different law firm,
我也可以理解
I understand.
你跟我一样清楚
You know as well as I do
没有别的律所会接手这个案子
nobody else is gonna take this case.
你说过  你在意那些人
You told me you cared about these people.
你向我保证过
You gave me your word.
是的  我也希望我能遵守诺言
Yeah, and I wish I could keep it.
我想惩罚那些混蛋  跟你想要钱的心情一样迫切
I want those bastards as much as you want this money,
但我没有证据
but I've got no proof,
而你也不是一个可信的证人
and you're not a credible witness.
-你又在这胡扯  -我没有胡扯
- Oh, that bullshit again. - That's not bullshit.
如果最开始你就跟我实话实说
If you had been straight with me from day one,
我们甚至不会陷进这个烂摊子
we wouldn't even be in this mess.
他们给你多少钱让你放弃这个案子
How much did they give you to dump the case?
肯定不少吧
Had to be something.
否则你不会出卖我的
Otherwise, you wouldn't sell me out.
很抱歉  乔  都结束了
I'm sorry, Joe. It's over.
你抱歉吗
You're sorry?
杰西卡
Jessica.
有事吗
Do you need something?
我来过一趟  你不在
I came by earlier, and you weren't in.
我有个会  我不认为
I had a meeting, and I really didn't think
你会对我的日程感兴趣
you wanted to be looped in on my schedule.
当然不  我不是来检查工作的
I don't, and I'm not checking up on you.
我只是不知道你来没来
I just didn't know if you were coming in.
你是说  你不确定我还来不来上班
You mean you weren't sure if I was ever coming in again.
你不是第一个因为私人原因
You wouldn't be the first person to leave a job
而辞掉工作的
for personal reasons.
听起来你已经有决定了
It sounds to me like you have an agenda.
-没有啊  -这可真稀奇
- I don't. - Well, that's a first.
你是说我来这儿就是为了逼你离开吗
Are you saying that I came here to push you out?
我是说  我还真不知道
I'm saying that I've never known you
你会不知道自己想要什么
not to know what you want.
我想要谈谈我们的事
What I want is to talk about us,
但你好像不想
but you don't seem to want to do that,
所以我只能专注于别的事
so I'm focusing on this.
我是不会在昨天发生的那些事之后
I'm not resigning my senior partnership
第二天立刻词去资深合伙人的
the day after what happened happened,
如果你想问这个的话
if that's what you're asking.
我想问  你打算辞职吗
I'm asking if you plan to resign it at all.
这个我没法回答  因为我也不知道
And I can't tell you that right now, because I don't know.
那么你什么时候能知道
Well, when will you know?
听着  杰西卡  你是经营合伙人
Look, Jessica, you're the managing partner,
所以如果你想让我离开  那随便你
so if you want to push me out, push me out,
但是如果你问我  我想怎么样
but if you're asking me what I want to do,
我的回答是  我还没决定
I'm telling you that I haven't decided.
怎么样
How did it go?
不要在意那些
Never mind how it went.
迈克呢  他起草文件了吗
Where's Mike. Did he file those papers?
我  我不知道  他还没来呢
I-I-I don't know. He's not even in yet.
告诉他  什么都不用写了
Well, you tell him not to file anything,
告诉他  不论他要对那女人做什么
and you tell him to do whatever he has to
尽管放手去做
stick it to that woman.
为什么
Why?
因为不管用
Because it didn't work.
什么不管用
What didn't work?
我试图跟伊凡做个交易
I tried to make a deal with Evan to trade the case.
你是说你要为了我撤销指控
You mean you offered to drop the case in exchange for me.
是的
Yes.
那现在我们要做什么
And now what are we gonna do?
你什么都不用做
You're not gonna do anything.
我要用尽各种手段
I'm gonna do whatever I have to
让泰伦斯·沃尔夫让步
to get Terrance Wolf to back off.
哈维  地方检察官不可能
Harvey, there's no way the D.A.
只是因为我为你工作
handles a case like this himself
就亲自处理这样的案件
just because I work for you.
他亲不亲自接手都没关系
Whether he handles it himself or not doesn't matter,
因为再过一个小时  这案子就不存在了
because this case won't even exist in another hour.
事情怎么样
How did it go?
我刚刚跟一个人说
I just told a man that everything
我之前的承诺都不算数了
I promised him was bullshit.
你觉得事情会怎么样
How do you think it went?
迈克  我很遗憾
Mike, I'm sorry.
你真应该看看他当时的表情
Oh, you should have seen his face.
那笔钱本会改变他的生活
That money was gonna change his life,
可我又当着他的面把他的希望打碎了
and then I dangled it in front of him and ripped it away.
但这不是你的错
Yeah, but it's not your fault.
你已经尽力了
You did everything you could.
他说我出卖了他
He accused me of selling out.
你知道你没有
You know you didn't do that.
我真的没有吗
Didn't I?
我们之所以放弃是因为...
We gave up because--
因为我吗
Of me?
我不是这个意思
That's not what I was gonna say.
你就是
Yeah, it was.
我本来要说是因为哈维的
No, I was gonna say because of Harvey.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
哈维一开始就不想接这个案子
Harvey never wanted to take this case,
所以他一直催着我放弃
so he put a clock on it to get me to drop it.
这就造成了我们现在的局面
That's why we're where we are right now.
听我说  哈维现在就在外面
Listen to me; Harvey is out there right now
拼了老命地在想办法补救
busting his ass to fix everything.
不  唐娜
No, Donna.
他根本就不在乎这个案子  从没在乎过
He doesn't give a shit about this case, and he never did.
那他为什么让我来告诉你
Then why did he send me here to tell you to do
要你不择手段对付伊凡·施密斯
everything you can to stick it to Evan Smith?
她没接受我们的条件  对吧
She didn't take the deal, did she?
她没接受
No, she didn't.
唐娜  我很遗憾
Donna, I'm sorry.
我忘了你还...
I didn't realize that you were still--
身处窘境吗
On the hot seat?
就像我说的  哈维正在想办法
Like I said, Harvey's busting his ass to fix it,
那就是说他会解决好
which means he's gonna fix it.
现在  去了结这一切
Now, finish what we started
想办法打赢这场官司
and figure out a way to win this case.
哈维·斯佩克特
Harvey Specter.
我还在想你会什么时候来呢
I was wondering when you would show up.
呵呵  我还在想你为什么
That's funny; I was wondering why
从来没给我寄过圣诞贺卡呢
you never sent me a Christmas card.
看起来你一点也不担心
You don't seem the least bit worried about
对你秘书的指控
the pending charges against your secretary.
当然不担心  她又没做错事
I'm not, because she did nothing wrong.
你知道我是怎么想的吗
Well, you know what I think?
我觉得要是她真是清白的  你就不会来了
I think you wouldn't be here if she did nothing wrong.
听我说  她什么也没偷
Listen to me. She didn't steal anything.
她说服他们放她进去  才拿到的文件
She got those documents by convincing them to let her in,
这不是犯罪
and that is not a crime.
上一次你来我办公室的时候
And the last time you were in my office,
你说你没有为了达到目的
you told me you hadn't committed a crime
而触犯法律
to get the job done.
我告诉过你  你错抓无辜
After I told you you had an innocent man,
可你只在乎程序
and all you cared about was procedure.
我只在乎法律
All I cared about was the law.
要是你真这么关心犯法的人
Well, if you're so concerned with people breaking the law,
怎么不去看看那些文件
why don't you take a look at those documents?
因为它们证明了自由铁路公司确实犯罪了
Because they prove Liberty Rail actually committed a crime,
而唐娜  只是因为为我工作而受到牵连
unlike Donna, whose only crime is working for me.
我调查她不是因为她为你工作
I'm not investigating her for working for you.
而是因为诈欺罪
I'm investigating her for felony fraud.
你在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
那个放她进去的女的一口咬定
The woman that let her in swears your secretary told her
你秘书说自己是国家运输管理局的人
she was with the National Transportation Safety Board.
那可是联邦机关
That's a federal agency,
那说法就不算是使小伎俩了
which makes what she did not a trick.
而是诈欺
It makes it felony fraud.
到我办公室来  马上
My office. Now.
关门
Close the door.
哈维  怎么了
Harvey, what happened?
怎么了  你骗了我
What happened is, you lied to me.
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
你告诉他们的秘书你是国家运输管理局的人
You told their secretary you were with the NTSB?
-那不是我的原话  -胡扯
- That's not what I said. - Bullshit.
你骗我的时候我就知道你在胡扯
I know when I've been lied to.
现在马上给我说清楚
Come clean right now.
我...
I--
他妈的马上不懂吗
Right the hell now.
我没说过我是他们的人
I never said I was with them.
原话是  "你有没有听说过"
I said, "Have you ever heard of
"国家运输管理局"
the National Transportation Safety Board?"
有什么区别吗
How is that any different?
-对不起  我...  -对不起有屁用
- I'm sorry, I-- - You're sorry?
哈维  我真不知道这么说是犯法的
Harvey, I swear I didn't know that that made it a crime.
我明确问你的时候你就知道了
You knew when I point-blank asked you,
但是你对我说了谎
and you lied to me about it.
我以为你会处理好的
Well, I thought that you would take care of it.
要是你连实话都不告诉我
How can I take care of it
我怎么能处理好
if you don't tell me the goddamn truth?
你以为我不想实话实说吗
Do you think that I didn't want to tell you the truth?
-那你为什么不说  -因为我很惭愧
- Then why didn't you? - Because I was ashamed.
我知道这听起来很傻
I know that it sounds stupid,
但是你和迈克他们  总能像变戏法那样
but you and Mike and everyone pull these rabbits
想出一个又一个办法
out of your hats all the time,
而我却只能坐在外面接电话
and I just sit outside, and I answer the phones.
可是我搞到了这些文件  人们就把我当救星
And then I got those documents, and people said I saved the day.
还没等我反应过来  你就已经在我面前
And the next thing I knew, you were on my doorstep
像看罪犯一样看着我
coming at me like I was some sort of criminal,
我被吓到了  所以我撒谎了
and I panicked, and I lied.
-唐娜  -对不起  哈维
- Donna-- - I'm sorry, Harvey.
我知道  但这导致
I know you are, but this just got
我摆脱这事的难度上升了一千倍
1,000 times harder for me to get out of.
你是指帮我摆脱这件事吧
You mean for you to get me out of.
唐娜  到现在你最该知道
Donna, you of all people should understand by now
对于我来说  我们不分彼此
that to me they're the same thing.
你来这儿干嘛
What are you doing here?
我去你单位找你  他们说你请了病假
I went to see you at work. They said you called in sick.
我说了  你来干嘛
I said, what are you doing here?
我想告诉你个好消息
I wanted to tell you the good news.
我不会放弃你的案子了
I'm not dropping your case after all.
你高兴就好
Good for you.
乔
Hey, Joe.
我知道你觉得自己被耍了
I know you've been jerked around,
但是事情会改变的
but things are gonna change.
会改变吗  真的吗
Gonna change? Really?
你不是说拿到证据的方式不正当吗
I thought you said you got the evidence in the wrong way.
可你不是说用正当的方式就好了吗
Well, and you said we should get it in the right way,
而这正是我们要做的
so that's exactly what we're gonna do.
我说过了  你爱咋地咋地  与我无关
Like I said, good for you, but you're not gonna do it with me.
乔
Hey, Joe.
没有正当委托人  我不能传唤那些记录
I can't subpoena those records without the legitimate client.
要是这么做的话  我根本没有立场
I have no basis and no standing to move forward if I did.
现在你有时间来跟我解释程序问题了
Oh, now you have time to explain procedure to me, right?
好  是我活该
Okay, fine. I deserved that.
但是  这个案子不能没有你  乔
But, Joe, this case cannot move forward without you.
你在放弃我之前就应该想到这些的
You should have thought of that before you cut me loose.
他们来找你了对吧
They got to you, didn't they?
付了你封口费
They gave you a few dollars to shut you up,
跟你达成了无罪协议
and then they sealed the agreement with no admission of guilt.
你知道吗
You know what?
我不能议论这件事  你也知道原因
I can't comment on that, and you know why,
但是有一点我们得说清楚
but let's get one thing straight.
不是他们让我闭的嘴  是你
They didn't shut me up; you did.
就算我接受了什么
And if I took anything,
那也是因为我没有选择的余地
it was because I had no other choice.
乔  听我说
Joe, listen to me.
如果支票还没有兑现  我们还有机会
If the check hasn't cleared, we can still get out of it.
不要再来这里了
Don't come by here anymore.
你对那些人的在乎也就这么多嘛
So much for really caring about those people.
见鬼去吧
Go to hell.
谁把小宝贝安排到角落坐了
I thought nobody puts baby in the corner.
我怎么成了"小宝贝"
Since when am I "Baby"?
你坐在角落里啊
Since you're sitting in the corner.
你通常都是众人瞩目的女生
You're usually a power table kind of girl.
今晚我不是
Well, I'm not tonight.
杰西卡  怎么了
Jessica, what's going on?
我和杰夫结束了
It's over between me and Jeff.
什么  怎么回事
What? What happened?
不重要了
It's not important.
昨天他打电话给我说要带你去巴黎
One day the man is calling me about taking you to Paris,
今天就结束了
and the next it's over,
这么大转变的原因还不重要
and the reason for all that isn't important?
不  因为现在
No, it isn't, because right now,
我得决定他是否该留在律所里
I have to decide whether he should stay at the firm.
那我得说这分手的原因很重要
Well, then I'd say the reason that you broke up is important.
我现在不想谈这个
And I don't want to get into it right now,
木已成舟
because it's not going to change.
这话很耳熟啊
Wow, heard that before.
丽娅  我跟爸爸不一样  别再说我像了
Leah, I'm not like Dad, and I'm tired of hearing it.
我知道你总说你不像他
I know you always say you're not like him,
但你现在不去挽回你爱的人
but here you are scrubbing up for the next surgery
反倒像他一样在准备下一场手术了
instead of fighting for the man that you love.
你知道吗
You know what?
大多数姐妹会说  "真遗憾  杰西卡"
Most sisters would say, "I'm sorry, Jessica,"
然后给我一个拥抱
and then give me a hug.
杰西卡  我很遗憾你受伤了
Jessica, I am sorry that you're hurting,
但如果你想要甜蜜慰藉
and if you want something sugarcoated,
我会帮你点甜点  但我们不是这么扶持对方的
I'll order you dessert, but that is not how we show support.
没错
You're right.
我们扶持的方式是分享想法  那你...
We show it by telling each other what we think, so...
我想的是
And what I think is,
两天前这个男人还爱着你
two days ago, this man loved you.
所以除非你劈腿或者偷了他的钱
So unless you cheated on him, stole from him,
或者杀了人  在我看来你们
or killed somebody, it seems to me the two of you
应该可以想办法挽回这段感情
should be able to get past whatever it is you did do.
乔·亨德森不干了
Joe Henderson backed out.
哈维  你听见我说话了吗
Harvey, did you hear me?
他们花钱封了他的口  我们没案子可告了
They paid him off. We have no case anymore.
现在我有个更大的麻烦
And right now, I have a bigger problem.
唐娜说谎了
Donna lied.
什么意思  她说谎了
What do you mean, she lied?
我是说她不只是混进了档案室
I mean she didn't just bullshit her way into that file room.
她还用了"国家交通安全局"的名头
She used the words "National Transportation Safety Board."
在什么情况下说的
In what context?
在不惜犯罪来帮你的情况下
In the context of committing a crime to help you.
你是在指责我知道她这么做了吗
Are you accusing me of knowing that she did that?
如果你不知道  是因为你不想知道
If you didn't know, it's because you didn't want to know.
哈维  她告诉我她没偷那些文件
Harvey, she told me she didn't steal those things.
我和你一样相信了
I believed her the same way you did.
那你就像她一样说谎了
And you lied just like she did.
我没说谎
I did not lie.
那为什么我问你这些文件哪儿来的之后
Then how come when I asked you where those documents came from,
你怎么一个字没提唐娜的事
you didn't say one word about Donna?
因为如果我说了  你就什么都
Because you wouldn't have listened to another word
听不下去了  我是在完成任务
I said after that, and I was trying to get the job done.
你为了完成任务不惜让她冒险
Well, you got the job done by risking her.
这和你以前让我冒风险有什么不同
And how is that different than all the times you risked me?
因为她和你不同
Because she's different.
哈维  我发誓我不知道
Harvey, I swear I didn't know.
我已经说了  现在麻烦更大了
Well, like I said, right now, I've got a bigger problem.
唐娜会面临诈骗罪指控
Donna's gonna be charged with felony fraud,
她还是有罪的
and she's guilty.
-五要素  -什么
- Five elements. - What?
证明诈骗成立有五个要素
Proving fraud consists of five elements.
好  我知道  但全满足
Okay, I'm aware of that, and they have all of them.
伤害呢
What about injury?
唐娜怎么给自由铁路公司造成伤害了
How did Donna injure Liberty Rail?
-你心知肚明  -我们都清楚
- You know how. - I know, and you know.
但伊凡·施密斯不会坐在陪审团前
But Evan Smith isn't gonna sit in front of a jury
解释清楚那些档案的意义
and explain why those documents have value
同时又不提她客户面临的刑事指控
without exposing her client to criminal charges.
没有造成损害
And without damages,
唐娜的行为最多只是非法入侵
what Donna did is trespassing at the worst.
你要我怎么做
What do you want me to do?
我要你继续这个民事案件
I want you to stay on the civil case.
哈维  这个案子已经没戏了
Harvey, the lawsuit is dead.
我们没有原告
We don't have a plaintiff.
那就去找一个  因为我不会
Then get another one, because I'm not letting
那个女人得到任何好处
this woman get away with a goddamn thing.
好吧
All right,
我只是出于礼貌见你一下
I'm paying you the courtesy of a meeting.
你有什么想法
What's on your mind?
依他一贯名声看  我敢说
Well, based on his reputation, I would say that
他打算逃避这个起诉
he's going to try to weasel his way out of this.
我是打算帮沃尔夫先生
What I'm going to do is save Mr. Wolf
摆脱在法庭公开受窘的情形
from being embarrassed in open court.
我敢说你这么做没什么附带好处吧
And I'm sure there's no side benefit to you in the process.
你知道你这么做会让史密斯女士
You do know you're gonna have to put Ms. Smith
上证人席对吧
on the stand, right?
你也是啊  所以她才会到这地步
So do you; that's why you had her come down here.
她告诉你唐娜究竟拿了什么东西吗
And did she tell you what Donna actually took?
你告诉我的
You told me what Donna took.
我还告诉你这是用来证明他们犯了罪
And I also told you that it proves they committed a crime,
但她不能这么说  所以唐娜偷的东西
but she can't say that, which means all Donna stole
只是一叠废纸
was a meaningless stack of papers,
没有任何伤害
and without actual damages--
我也懂法律
I know the law.
那你知道你的证人多不靠谱了
Then you know you've got a shitty witness.
是吗
Well?
我不能透露那些文档的细节
I can't get into the details of those documents,
但这不表示那些文件没有价值
but that doesn't mean that they don't have value.
它们当然有价值  替你保命
Of course they have value. The saved you ass.
那是机密文件  有商业秘密
They're confidential. They have trade secrets.
唯一的秘密就是
The only secret that is in there
你们的火车害死人
is that your trains kill people.
好吧  够了
All right, enough.
史密斯女士  如果你不能证明伤害
Ms. Smith, if you can't show damages,
我就没案可立
I have no case.
你不需要损害
You don't need damages.
有意图就够了
You have intent.
如果你真的了解我
And if you really knew my reputation,
你知道我以前在这里干过
you'd also know that I used to work here.
我告诉你在地区检察官的历史上
And I can tell you they've never gone after anyone for intent
就没有仅靠意图就起诉的案例
in the history of the D.A.'s office,
他们现在也不会开此先例
and they're not gonna start now.
很高兴和你打交道  伊凡
It was good doing business with you, Evan.
事情顺利吗
Hey. How are things?
你是说哈维说会
You mean the things that you said that Harvey
搞定的那些事情吗
would take care of?
没错  我就是说那些事
Yes, those are exactly the things I mean.
那些事情
Well, those are exactly the things
哈维的确搞定了
that Harvey just took care of.
是吗
He did?
是的
He did.
路易  怎么了
Louis, what's wrong?
没事
Nothing's wrong.
只是  我知道肯定不可能
It's just... I know it wasn't gonna happen,
但当你告诉我他们要起诉你时
but when you first told me they might press charges,
我不禁想到你被关起来...
the thought of you behind bars...
别这样
Oh, come on.
就算被关也是去轻松的白领罪犯度假地
It just would have been some cushy, white-collar resort.
我可能终于会有机会拿瑜伽认证了
I could have finally gotten my yoga certification--
不会的
It wouldn't have been.
但没关系  因为我说对了
But it doesn't matter, because I was right.
哈维想尽了一切办法
Harvey did whatever it took.
谢谢  路易
Thanks, Louis.
他根本不知道拥有你是多幸运的一件事
God, he doesn't even know how lucky he is to have you.
诺玛还没来  对吧
Norma's still out, isn't she?
她那个天杀的姐姐绊了一跤摔进了浴缸
Her goddamn sister tripped and fell in the tub,
她去帮忙了
and she went to help.
她好像一点都不在乎我
It's like she doesn't even care about me at all.
我知道你不在维修部上班
I know you don't work in maintenance,
但你有权查阅账单
but you do have access to accounts payable,
如果你...
so if you could...
别  拜托  听我...
look--no--hey, please, just hear me...
该死
God damn it.
又一个不接你电话的
Another one wouldn't take your call?
没人会听我说
No, none of them will.
我给整张名单上的人都打过电话
I've been through this entire directory.
只要我一提"车祸""热""感应器"这几个词
As soon as I use the words "Crash," "Heat," Or "Sensors,"
他们就不肯再说了
they all stop talking.
迈克  有人死了
Mike, people died.
一定会有人想要声张正义
Somebody's got to want to do the right thing.
就算有人  我也找不到
Well, if somebody does, I can't find them.
受害者家属呢
Okay what about the victims' families?
你是说最初的原告吗
Oh, you mean the original plaintiffs.
问题是  他们已经和解了
Yeah, the problem is, they already have a settlement.
看看吧
Go on. Look at it.
铁路公司不傻
They weren't stupid.
和解书使受害者家属再也不能追究他们的责任
It prevents them from ever going after them again.
迈克  我只是想帮忙
Mike, I'm just trying to help you.
我知道  抱歉
I know you are. I'm sorry.
我只是很沮丧
I'm just frustrated.
如果找不到新原告  我就没法继续受理此案
If I can't find a new plaintiff, I can't keep this case alive.
等等
Wait a second.
你说公司里没人愿意跟你谈
You said no one at the company will talk to you.
是啊  因为他们都害怕丢了饭碗
They won't, because they're all afraid they'll lose their job.
如果那个人再没什么可以失去的呢
All right, so what about someone who has nothing left to lose?
什么意思
What are you talking about?
我说的是他
I'm talking about him.
我帮你重新安排了之前错过的和莱瑟姆的会面
So I rescheduled the meeting that you missed with Latham
明天下午三点
for 3:00 tomorrow.
这是最新的合同
Here are the newest contracts.
凯西·芬恩就收购的事打电话过来
Also, Kathy Finn called about the takeover,
我给了她最新细则  告诉她稍安勿躁
so I sent her the latest specs, and I told her to sit tight.
我还注意到你桌上左边那支笔没水了
And I noticed the left pen on your desk set was out of ink,
我帮你换了笔芯
so I had the cartridge replaced.
这些事可以在我不在的时候做
You could have done all of this while I was out of the office.
我知道  但那样我就没机会向你道谢了
I know, but then I wouldn't have had a chance to thank you.
唐娜
Donna.
谢谢你  哈维
Thank you, Harvey.
不用谢
You're welcome.
保尔森女士  斯佩克特先生
Ms. Paulsen, Mr. Specter.
泰伦斯  你最好是来代地检署
Terrance, you better be here to give Donna a formal apology
向唐娜正式道歉的
from the D.A.'s office.
不
No.
我是来把这个给她的律师
I'm here to give her lawyer this.
哈维  是什么
Harvey, what is that?
唐娜  你出去
Donna, leave the room.
你可以让她出去
You can tell her to leave.
但别忘了告诉她
Don't forget to tell her
明早九点法庭要传讯她
her arraignment's 9:00 a.m. tomorrow morning.
传讯  因为什么
Arraignment? For what?
你个婊子养的
You son of a bitch.
你把指控改成了意图诈骗
You amended the charges to intent?
你说地检署史上
You said it's never been done
从没这样做过
in the history of the D.A.'s office.
我决定创造历史
I decided to make history.
通过对付一个什么都没偷的人
By going after someone for stealing nothing.
她进去找希望之钻
She went in there to find the Hope Diamond.
就算只带走了一块玻璃
Just because she came out with a piece of glass
也不代表那不是欺诈
doesn't mean it wasn't fraud.
本来就不是
That's exactly what it means.
每次我抓到你
Every time I run into you,
你都说你做下的肮脏勾当
you tell me whatever shady thing just went down
是为了大局  或是根本没做过
was about the greater good or that it didn't happen
或是因为这个  因为那个  但这是犯罪
or this, that, or the other, but a crime was committed here,
我要因此追究她的责任
and I'm going after her for it.
扯淡  你是想对付我
Bullshit. You're going after me.
你是说你没命令她偷东西
Oh, you're telling me you didn't order her to do it.
没有
No, I didn't.
我们会查清楚的
Well, we'll find out...
她即将被判有罪的时候
when she's about to be convicted
我会给她份协议
and I offer her a deal.
现在怎么办
What happens now?
明天去接受传讯
What happens now is, we go in there tomorrow
进行无罪抗辩
and enter a plea of not guilty.
但我有罪
But I am guilty.
唐娜  意图诈骗这种指控根本是无稽之谈
Donna, intent to commit fraud is a bullshit charge,
他只是想借此来吓唬你
and he's just using you to try to scare you.
起码管用  我被吓倒了
Well, it's working. I'm scared.
-唐娜  -可能判什么刑
- Donna-- - What's the punishment?
这不重要  因为我会帮你脱罪
It doesn't matter, because I'm gonna get you out of it.
哈维  会怎么判
Harvey, what's the punishment?
可能判什么刑
Three to five years.
天啊
Oh, my God.
-什么三到五年  -现在没空  路易
- Three to five years for what? - Not now, Louis.
我刚在电梯那看到泰伦斯·沃尔夫
I just saw Terrance Wolf at the elevator.
什么三到五年
Three to five years for what?
他起诉她意图诈骗
He's charging her with intent to commit fraud.
该死
Holy shit.
路易  我不想听
Louis, I don't want to hear it.
你必须听  因为你本应该
Well, you're going to, because you were supposed to
帮她摆脱这摊破事
get her out of this.
你这样于事无补
This isn't helping.
那你以为我之前在干什么
What the hell do you think I've been doing?
不知道  但不管你做了什么  都毫无用处
I don't know, but whatever it is, it didn't do a thing.
你根本不知道你在说什么
You have no idea what you're talking about.
我告诉她你永远不会让她有麻烦
I told her that you were never gonna let her get in trouble.
没这么简单
It's not so simple.
怎么就不简单了
What the hell isn't so simple?
她有罪
She's guilty.
沃尔夫想利用她来对付我
Wolf is trying to use her to turn on me,
因为他认为是我让她做的
because he thinks I put her up to it.
是你吗
Did you?
哈维毫不知情
Harvey didn't even know I did it.
无所谓了
You know what? It doesn't even matter.
-这案子我来办  -不行
- Because I'm taking over. - No, you're not.
他想利用她来对付你
He's trying to get her to turn on you.
你不能当她的律师
You cannot be her lawyer.
她不会背叛我  有什么区别
She's not going to, so what difference does it make?
区别在于
The difference is,
如果你不插手  沃尔夫就会让步
if you're out of the picture, Wolf backs down.
在他看来  我已经牵扯其中
From where he's standing, I'm in the picture,
他不会让步的
and he's never gonna back down.
这可未必  这事关唐娜的人生
You don't know that, and this is Donna's life.
我不会把她的人生交到你手里
And I'm not putting it in your hands.
这不是你能决定的
And it's not your decision to make.
确实  这要唐娜来决定
No, it's not. It's Donna's.
她跟我一伙
And she's sticking with me.
路易  拜托  我知道你想帮忙
Louis, please, I know that you want to help,
但你还是走吧
but just go.
-亚沃尔斯基先生  -是我
- Mr. Jaworski. - Yeah.
我是皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特律所的迈克·罗斯
My name is Mike Ross. I'm with Pearson Specter Litt.
这位是瑞秋·赞恩
This is Rachel Zane.
我们律所的律师
She's one of our associates.
先生  我们想跟你谈谈那起事故
Sir, we'd like to speak with you about the accident.
我已经做过证了
Look, I was already deposed for that lawsuit.
受害者得到了赔偿
The victims got paid.
我能说的也都说了
I said everything I had to say, okay?
我们不是来追究你
We're not here to come after you.
我们想让你起诉自由铁路公司
We want you to sue Liberty Rail.
是吗  我为什么要起诉他们
Oh, yeah? And why would I sue them?
因为虽然火车是你驾驶的
'Cause while you might have been driving the train,
但事故不是你的错
that accident wasn't your fault.
你在逗我吗
Is this some kind of a joke?
不  先生  不是的
No, sir. It isn't.
他们让你做了替罪羊
They made you the fall guy.
放屁  他们为什么要这么做
Bullshit. Why would they do that?
因为他们得归罪于某人
Because they needed to blame someone,
而你不但是驾驶员
and not only were you at the wheel,
还不记得发生什么事了
you had no memory of what happened.
不  我不相信
Nah, I don't believe it.
他们是家好公司  他们不会这么做的
They're a good company. They wouldn't do this.
亚沃尔斯基先生...
Mr. Jaworski--
听着  是我害死了那些人
Look, I killed those people.
这种情况下他们还同意算我提早退休
And they still gave me early retirement
同时还继续给我发退休金
and let me keep my pension.
他们之所以那样做是为了让你不闹事
The reason they did that was to keep you quiet.
我要你们滚出我家
I need you to get off my property,
你们两个
both of you.
先生  你知道我们说的是真相
Sir, you know that we're telling the truth.
是啊  但是这个真相能帮一个余生
Yeah, well, is the truth gonna support the family of a guy
都无法再找一份工作的人养家糊口吗
who can't get another job for the rest of his life?
假如我们赢了  你就衣食无忧了
If we win, you'll be set up for life.
你们看看我
Ah, take a look at me.
我不是那种能赢的人
I ain't the guy who wins.
我就是那种注定会输的人
I'm the guy who loses.
假如我能保证料理好一切呢
What if I can guarantee to take care of all of that
无论发生什么
no matter what happens.
你们需要我做什么
What would you need me to do?
全体起立
All rise.
你还好吧
You okay?
我要发言吗
Am I gonna have to talk?
你就恭恭敬敬说"法官大人"就好
Just be polite and say "Your Honor."
不等你反应过来一切就结束了
It will be over before you know it.
州地检起诉唐娜·鲍尔森
State versus Donna Paulsen.
辩护律师准备好继续提审了吗
Is the defense counsel prepared to proceed with the arraignment?
准备好了  法官大人
We are, Your Honor.
鲍尔森女士  你被诉
Ms. Paulsen, you have been charged
意图诈骗的重罪
with felony intent to commit fraud.
这将导致最高五年的监禁判决
This carries a maximum sentence of up to five years in prison.
你清楚今天对你的指控吗
Do you understand the charges against you today?
清楚  法官大人
Yes, Your Honor.
你有什么要辩护的吗
How do you plead?
无罪辩护  法官大人
Not guilty, Your Honor.
很好
Very well.
沃尔夫先生  地检准备好进行庭审了吗
Mr. Wolf, is the state ready to go to trial?
准备好了  法官大人
We are, Your Honor.
庭审安排在周一开始
Trial is set to begin Monday.
下一案
Next case.
好了  你的意思我明白了
All right, you made your point.
我们把这案子辩护成轻罪
Let's plead this down to a misdemeanor
然后回去干正事吧
and both go back to our real jobs.
这就是我的正事
This is my real job.
假如你对这个所代表的东西还留有一丝尊敬的话
Maybe if you had a little more respect for what it stands for,
你就不会站在这里了
you wouldn't be standing here.
听着  我要从你自鸣得意的脸上把那个表情抹去
Listen, I'm gonna wipe that look off your smug face.
你尽管试试  哈维
You give it a try, Harvey,
但是我掌握了所需的一切证据
but I've got all the evidence I need.
你得为自己找个新秘书了
You're gonna have to go find yourself a new secretary.
我看你又开始不敲门了
I see you're back to not knocking.
我就当这代表你已经下定决心了
I take it that means you've made up your mind.
的确
I have.
然后
And,
我决定
what I've decided
你那晚将我拒之门外
is that you shut the door on me the other night,
让你来规定我做过什么
and it's not fair for you to dictate
却不让我申辩是不公平的
what I do and don't get to say.
我早告诉过你了
I told you.
无论你想说什么都不重要
It doesn't matter what you have to say,
因为不管怎样  我都不会相信的
because whatever it is, I won't believe it.
那假如我是来告诉你我爱你呢
Well, what if I was here to tell you that I love you?
杰西卡  你骗了我几个月...
Jessica, you lied to me for months--
杰夫  拜托
Jeff, please.
听我说
Just listen.
我知道我伤害了你
I know I hurt you,
但是是你希望
but you were the one
我们能一起工作  开始一段恋情的
who wanted us to work together and be in a relationship.
而是你觉得这是个错误的
And you were the one who thought it was a mistake.
因为我害怕了
Because I was scared.
但我改变注意了
But I changed my mind,
因为你拒绝放弃
because you refused to give up.
而如今我也拒绝放弃
And now I'm refusing to give up.
我希望你能留在这里
I want you to stay here.
我希望我们能工作感情兼得
I want us to have both.
杰西卡...
Jessica--
你曾经希望我能放下心墙
You wanted me to let my walls down.
现在放下了
Well, they're down.
唐娜  你为什么不回家
Donna, why don't you go home?
你知道我准备上庭时喜欢一个人静静
You know I like to be alone when I'm getting ready for a trial.
我要和你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
怎么了
What is it?
我觉得路易也许是对的
I think maybe Louis was right.
你觉得路易什么东西对了
You think Louis was right about what?
也许应该让他来接手我的案子
Maybe he should be handling my case.
好吧  假如你这么觉得的话
Okay, well, if that's how you feel.
我知道你会觉得这是侮辱
I knew it; I knew you would take this as an insult.
不然你想让我怎么看
How exactly would you like me to take it?
我希望你能严肃看待
I would like you to take it seriously
并且和我谈谈这件事
and talk about it with me.
好吧  唐娜
Okay, Donna,
你到底为什么想要路易接手
why exactly would you prefer Louis to handle this?
因为我今天去参加那个传讯
Because I sat in that arraignment today,
第一次意识到
and it hit me for the first time
我可能真的要进监狱了
that I might actually go to prison.
而你更在乎攻击泰伦斯·沃尔夫
And you were more concerned with attacking Terrance Wolf
而不是我
than you were with me.
所以你觉得路易是对的
So you think Louis is right.
我把地方检察官惹得太不高兴了
I piss off the D.A. too much.
你今天的确如此
Well, you sure did today.
那是因为他在针对我们
Because he's coming at us.
而你在火上浇油
And you're pouring gas on the fire.
因为那就是我的行事风格
Because that's what I do,
而我不需要你
and I don't need you
在事后走进这里来批评我的工作方式
coming in here second-guessing how I do my job.
哈维  你为什么要攻击我
Harvey, why are you attacking me?
我不是你的敌人
I'm not the enemy.
你现在绝对是了
You sure as hell are right now.
什么  为什么我会是...
What? Why am I the--
因为我正在准备打仗
Because I'm getting ready for a fight,
而你却来告诉我你不觉得我能赢
and you're telling me you don't think I can win.
我不是这个意思
I'm not telling you that.
我是在告诉你我吓坏了
I'm telling you that I'm petrified.
我理解  但我没时间来安慰你
And I understand, but I don't have time to comfort you.
那我需要你挤点时间
Well, I need you to make time.
我做不到  因为...
And I can't, because--
哈维  这是我的人生
Harvey, this is my life!
当我告诉路易你是怎么帮我从这件事里脱身时
When I told Louis how you got me out of this thing,
他告诉我一想到我要进监狱
he told me how scared he was at the thought
他是多么的害怕
of me going to prison,
而我只是...
and I just...
需要...
need...
你...
you...
来...
to--
唐娜  一想到你要进监狱了
Donna, the thought of you going to prison
我就吓得膝盖一软
makes me want to drop to my knees.
你想听我说出来吗
You want to hear me say it?
我说了
There it is.
但那不会发生的
But that's not gonna happen,
因为我不会允许这件事发生的
because I'm not gonna let it happen.
但是要做到这一点
But in order to do that,
你得让我做好我要做的事
you need to let me do what I do.
-哈维...  -够了
- Harvey-- - That's enough.
你想找人给你个拥抱吗
You want someone to give you a hug?
去找路易
Go to Louis.
你想找人帮你从这件事里脱身
You want someone to get you out of this thing,
你就得让我一个人静静
you need to leave me alone.
我要知道你掌握的一切
I need to know everything you have,
马上就要知道
and I need to know right now.
我们让驾驶员答应了
We got the conductor to sign on,
但是我们得给他...
but we have to give him--
我不在乎我要给他什么
I don't care what I have to give him.
只在乎那能给我们带来什么
What does that give us?
什么意思  能给我们立案的资格
What do you mean? It gives us standing.
现在我们可以用传票传唤那些记录了
Now we can subpoena those records.
那还不够
Well, that's not enough.
-至少是个开始啊  -我要的不是开始
- It's a start. - I don't need a start.
是结果  而且立刻就要
I need a finish, and I need it now.
他们要起诉唐娜了是吗
They're charging Donna, aren't they?
今天早上被传讯的
She was arraigned this morning.
如果上庭  我没法保证能赢
If this thing goes to trial, I can't guarantee a win.
那你又要为唐娜放弃这个案子了是吗
So we're back to trading the case for Donna.
是的  而且我不想听你那套
Yeah, and I don't want to hear your moral objections
不该让杀人犯漏网的道德说辞
about those people getting away with murder.
我没打算那么说  哈维
I'm not talking about that, Harvey,
但如果唐娜已经被传讯了
but if Donna was arraigned,
就不是他们撤诉能解决的了
it's not up to them to drop the charges.
决定权在沃尔夫  你知道他不会撤诉
It's up to Wolf, and you know he's never gonna do that.
我不是要让他撤诉
I'm not talking about dropping the charges.
我是要抹掉整个案件
I'm talking about making this whole damn thing go away.
哈维  如果我没理解错
Harvey, if you're saying what I think you're saying,
你这是干扰司法公正
that's obstruction of justice.
在我看来  这才是公正
The way I see it, it's justice.
你知道我的意思
You know what I mean.
我知道  而且我不在乎
I do, and I don't give a shit.
-此事事关唐娜  -好吧  我懂了
- This is Donna. - All right, I get it.
但如果我的材料不够呢
But what if what I have isn't enough?
你自己说的  至少是个开始
Like you said, it's a start.
明天一早我要在桌上见到正式诉状
Have an official complaint on my desk by the morning.
-那你干什么去  -我去弄足够的材料
- And what are you gonna do? - I'm gonna get us enough.
行了  听见了听见了
All right, I hear you. I hear you.
知道我是谁吗
Do you know who I am?
不知道
No.
迈克·罗斯是我的手下
Yeah, Mike Ross works for me.
我不管
Hey, I don't give a shit.
一开始我就跟他说不要接你的案子
I told him not to take your case in the first place,
因为我知道你就是个诈骗犯
because I knew you were a goddamn shakedown artist,
但现在我在乎的人卷进了麻烦
but now someone I care about is in trouble,
就因为你拿钱走人了
because you took a payout.
滚出去
Get out of my face.
听我说
Listen to me.
如果你不听我们的话
If you don't do what we need you to do,
你会倒大霉
I will hurt you.
你最好做好了杀我的准备
You better be prepared to kill me,
因为我绝不会把钱还回去的
because I'm not gonna give that money back.
如果只是钱的问题
Well, if this is just about money,
那就没什么争的必要了
then we don't need to fight at all.
哈维  我都快养成见你的习惯了
Harvey, this is becoming a habit.
我见你比见之前三个男友的次数都多
I've seen you more than my last three boyfriends.
这并不让我意外
Somehow that doesn't surprise me.
你真幽默
You're funny.
我喜欢你
I like you.
但你来恐怕不是为了嘲笑我的恋爱史
But I know you're not here to mock my relationship,
你想说什么
so what's on your mind?
我们想给你这个
We wanted to give you this.
这是什么
What's this?
我们替迈克尔·亚沃尔斯基拟写的诉状
It's the lawsuit we filed on behalf of Michael Jaworski.
就是被你们当作替罪羊的那位
You know, the man you let take the fall for the accident.
迈克尔·亚沃尔斯基不可以上诉
Michael Jaworski can't sue--
什么
What?
起诉你吗  因为你很聪明
Sue you, because you were smart enough
会替他付账吗
to take care of his expenses?
现在替他付账的是我了
Well, now I'm taking care of his expenses.
现在可以立案了
And now we have standing,
我们要传唤你们提供这些文件
and we are going to subpoena those documents.
我是不是该怕的发抖呢
Am I supposed to start quaking in my boots?
当然不  我们知道如果你们能改报告
Nope, we know if you can doctor a report,
这些记录你们也能动手脚
you can alter those maintenance records.
我什么也没有篡改
I didn't alter anything.
乔·亨德森可不是这么说的
Well, that's not what Joe Henderson said.
他说你找到了他  承认了一切
He said you came to him, admitted everything,
还提出了一个让他住口的和解方案
and offered him a settlement to keep quiet.
我们什么也没承认  而且那是保密协定
We didn't admit anything, and that settlement is sealed.
你说的是这份吗
Oh, you mean this settlement?
我们有约在先的
We had an agreement.
伊凡  拿钱息事宁人的坏处就在于
Well, here's the thing about paying people off, Evan.
总有人能出更高的价
Someone can always pay them more.
他的话没有理查德·麦金泰尔先生的可靠
His word won't hold up against Richard McIntyre's.
他不会说是理查德·麦金泰尔先生指使的
Oh, he's not saying that Richard McIntyre put him up to it.
他说是你干的
He's saying you did.
胡说八道
That's bullshit.
那真的重要吗
And does that really matter?
你想要什么
What do you want?
你让写报告的作者消失了
You made the author of that report disappear.
也让乔·亨德森消失了
You made Joe Henderson disappear.
想想办法让唐娜的目击者也
Figure out a way to make the witness against Donna
改个说辞
change her tune.
这是妨碍司法公正
That's obstruction of justice.
那是你的问题
That's not my problem.
你这个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
决定权在你
It's your call.
也许人们会相信乔  也许不会
Maybe people will believe Joe, maybe they won't,
但怎样你恐怕都不但赚不到钱
but instead of making money,
还得用接下来的五年辛苦地在庭上
you're gonna be defending yourself in court
为自己做辩护了
for the next five years.
既然确信是我们干的  你真的会选择
You're so sure we did this, you're really gonna let us
为了你的秘书让我们逃出法网吗
get away with murder for your secretary?
我正是要这么做  就算让我再选一百次
You're damn right I am, and if I had to do it again,
我也绝不会犹豫
I'd do it 100 times.
这是什么
What's that?
你知道这是什么
You know that it is.
-杰夫  -杰西卡  你说的对
- Jeff -- - Jessica, you were right.
要么两者兼得  要么两者皆失
We either need to have both, or it's not going to work.
但你不想兼得
And you don't want both?
此刻起  我提出辞职
Effective immediately, I'm tendering my resignation.
那我祝你好运
Then I wish you luck.
也祝你好运  杰西卡
Good luck, Jessica.
还记得吗
Do you remember?
当然记得  就是在那发生的
Yes, of course I remember. It happened right there.
那都是你的错
Well, it was your fault,
是你害我大笑的
'cause you made me burst out laughing.
可不光是大笑吧
You didn't just burst.
你喷出了一块虾肉都飞到屋子那头了
You spat a piece of shrimp across the room
就落在我妈妈的头发上
and into the back of my mother's hair.
但因为厚厚的发胶她甚至都没感觉到
And she didn't even feel it because of all the hair spray,
结果虾就跟标签似的一直挂在那里
and it stuck in there like a tick.
太搞笑了
Oh, my God.
接下来的两个小时我都没好意思
I could hardly look at her or that boyfriend
看她和她男朋友
for the next two hours.
他叫什么来着
What was his name again?
谁在乎  笨蛋一个
Who cares? He was such a loser.
拜托  他可是你参加了那个
Oh, come on; he was the reason you had
糟糕透顶的派对的原因呢
that god-awful party in the first place.
谢谢你  哈维
Thank you, Harvey.
不用道谢了  你不是都谢过我了吗
You don't need to thank me. You already thanked me.
不  上次道谢是谢谢你救我
No, I thanked you for fixing it.
这次是谢谢你一晚上都没提这事
Now I'm thanking you for not bringing it up all night.
我想如果你愿意谈
I just figured if you wanted it brought up,
你会主动提  你看你这不是提起了吗
you'd bring it up, and now you have, so...
我说过不会让你出事
I told you I'd never let anything happen to you,
就绝对会遵守诺言
and I won't ever,
所以以后你再也不用害怕成那个样子了
so you don't ever have to feel scared like that again.
你不是说你不会安慰人吗
I thought you said you didn't do the comfort thing.
我没说我不会
I didn't say I didn't do it.
我说的是当时没时间
I said I didn't have time,
因为我在忙着救你的小命
because I was so busy saving your ass.
很抱歉质疑了你
I'm sorry I doubted you.
我也很抱歉吼了你
I'm sorry I snapped at you.
其他人对我失去信心
Anyone else every loses faith in me,
我根本不在乎
it doesn't matter.
但你不行
But with you, it's different.
我该走了
I should go.
为什么
Why?
你知道原因
You know why.
你知道我爱你  唐娜
You know I love you, Donna.